It's your man, Alex, and in this video,
I'm going to be showing you guys the
all-around best self-haircut during
quarantine. This includes the fade on
the sides and back of my head, as well
as cutting about 1 in off the top of my
head using hair cutting scissors. To
start with the self-hair cut, I'm going
to be using my wall super tapered two
clippers with no guard and the lever
closed to put in my initial guideline
around my head. I'm going up about 1 in
and then creating a slight downward
angle as it reaches around my occipital
ridge on the back of my head. Make sure
your guidelines are as straight as
possible to help make things easier when
you begin fading in the hard lines.
Do the exact same thing on the other
side of your head using your clippers
with no guard and the lever closed.
Always double check your work and run
the clippers through your head a few
times before you move on to the next
guideline. This will ensure you didn't
miss any loose hairs or leave any hair
patches.
[Music]
Now, using the number one guard with the
lever closed, we're going to go up about
1 in from our initial guideline. Make
sure you keep the same exact distance
from the initial guideline all around
your head. You want your haircut to be
even all around. So, make sure you go up
1 in on the right, back, and left side
of your head from that initial
guideline.
[Music]
made this
instinct.
[Music]
Do the exact same thing on the other
side of your head using the number one
guard and the lever closed. If you guys
need help understanding how I utilize my
mirrors when cutting my hair, check out
my self-haircut mirror setup with the
fade video, I will leave the link to
this video in the card section in the
upper right corner.
[Music]
I love this.
Using the number two guard with the
lever closed, go up another 1 in from
our previous guideline with the number
one guard. Again, the keys here are to
really make sure number one, your lines
are as perfectly straight as possible,
and number two, your lines are 1 in
apart from the previous guideline.
[Music]
Using two duck clips, I'm going to be
separating the sides and top of my hair
at my part line. This will ensure none
of the hair on top of my head gets cut
when using my clippers and thinning
shears. Still using the number two guard
lever closed, we're going up 1 in from
our previous guideline on the other side
of our head.
Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
I know those lines are looking real
crispy, but we're not finished yet.
Using your clippers with no guard and
now the lever halfway open, we're going
to be taking out the hard line from our
initial guideline. Make sure you are
flicking up and away from your head to
get rid of the hard line.
[Music]
Do the exact same thing on the other
side. Using no guard with the lever
halfway open, flick up and away to blend
in that hard line. A good tip would be
to use your other hand to pull down your
skin and ear to really stretch out your
skin. This will make going up your head
with the clippers a lot smoother.
I love this.
Do not go gentle into that good night.
[Music]
Now using the number one guard with the
lever halfway open, flick up and away
from your head to get rid of the next
hard guideline. Keep using your mirrors
and take it slow. A lot of you cutting
your hair have probably never cut your
own hair before, so make sure you take
it slow, stay patient, and really focus
on what you're doing.
[Music]
Do the exact same thing on the other
side of your head. Using the number one
guard with the lever halfway open, flick
up and away from your head to get rid of
the next hard guideline.
[Music]
Using the number two guard with the
lever halfway open, we're going to flick
up and away to get rid of the final hard
guideline. For some of you, this step
may not matter. For example, if you do
not want a lot of hair by your part
line, you can just run the number two or
number three guard all the way up into
your part line to give yourself the
undercut look. But for me, I always like
to leave my hair longer by the part line
to give my hair a smoother transition as
it falls from the top to the sides of my
head.
[Music]
Now, busting out my thinning shears and
comb, I'm going to be blending in the
hair by my part line, as well as
removing some of the bulk so my hair can
have a more natural look.
So, a quick update for everyone on
what's going on with my life. I've been
working non-stop on a project for the
past few weeks, and I plan on finishing
this project sometime by the end of
June. This project is really going to
help every single one of you in so many
ways. You'll be learning practical,
hands-on information that has taken me
over 10 years to build up and condense
into a powerful educational platform.
You guys will be able to call yourself a
self-haircut expert and start saving
hundreds of dollars every year and
potentially making hundreds of dollars
every year cutting your own hair,
cutting your friend's hair, and your
family's hair. So, I'm really excited to
share this project with all of you, and
I will keep you updated on its progress
as the weeks go on.
Boy, we're looking crispier than crisp.
So, right now, I'm going to be
completely wetting my hair on top of my
head and then ring out the excess water
using my hands and a paper towel. If you
guys haven't seen my original
self-haircut video, it's got about 6.4
million views on it, and this was the
last time I cut more than 1 in off the
top of my head. I'll leave this video
linked in the card section above. But
just like in that video, I'm going to be
creating a middle part down my head to
work on what I call the perimeter
guideline. If you cannot do this
properly, you will completely jack up
your hair. But remember, that's why I'm
here to help you not make that mistake.
Always cut your hair on a 45° angle so
your hair is longer in the front and
shorter in the back. Like I just
mentioned, I'm cutting about 1 in off
the top. So, I'm doing the same thing
with the perimeter guideline.
[Music]
Now, using my perimeter guideline, I'm
going to start on the back left corner
of my head and then work my way over
using the same guideline to the right
side of my head. using the perimeter
guideline to create a new guideline in
the middle of your head. And make sure
when you are cutting your hair, cut
straight across to make all of the hair
completely even. Then once you finish
the back of your hair, work your way to
the middle and the front of your head
using the existing perimeter guideline
in their given sections.
[Music]
If you guys like this video so far, make
sure you follow me on Instagram, Alex
Kuras. I post a lot of funny behind the
scenes, and I always do my best to
answer any questions you may have for me
about your hair and your self-haircut.
[Music]
As you can see, I'm running my hands
through my hair, double-checking my work
to make sure every section is even and
has that nice graduation from short in
the back to longer in the front.
Boy, you already know what I'm about to
say.
My hair is looking super fresh and that
fade is barber status. But I want to
finish this haircut off with a nice
style. And I will be using my quick sand
and gravity paste from Hans Dukco.
Taking about a P-siz amount of each, rub
the product into your hands to really
emulsify and heat it up. Then start
running the product all around your
head. Don't be afraid to smack yourself
around and get the product into the
roots of your hair.
[Music]
Instinct
w.
So, here's the before and after of my
haircut. I'm looking forward to seeing
you guys cut your hair just like I did
here. I can't wait to share with you
guys my project that's coming real soon.
And if you guys like it, please give it
a thumbs up. If you're new to my
channel, make sure you guys hit that
subscribe button down below. I
appreciate it so much. But thank you all
so much for watching and I'll catch you
next time. Peace.